Good morning. This is the program with
Ted R and John Kuryaku. It is Tuesday,
January 13th. Thank you so much for
joining us. Uh today we will be uh
introducing um some merch you can buy.
Um we're also going to uh happy to
announce that uh Robbie Aid is fulfilled
for the month of January. But if you are
so moved and you would like to tip
Robbie because he can certainly use the
cash, um please go ahead to
gofundme.com/dprogram
Robbie. Uh we're going to be talking
about the ongoing uh fallout from the
killing of Renee Good. Um the situation
in Gaza, which has been fallen off the
headlines, but is still sucking hard uh
for the people there who have survived.
Uh certainly the crisis in Iran and uh
Malaysia and Indonesia have become the
two first countries to block Grock and I
believe uh any AI platform over deep
fake porn. And by the way, even poor
Renee Good has been virtually undressed
by Grock. Uh it turns out
>> it's just nuts. People are nuts. Like
you have nothing better to do with your
time.
>> No [__]
>> You take a dead woman's picture and and
use AI to make her naked. Yeah. What
what pleasure do people get out of
something like that? I [sighs] It's just
too weird for me.
>> I know. Well, and also as a former
programmer, I know this is something
that could easily be stopped. Um if it's
just a little bit of code, um not so
hard. Uh but anyway, good morning, John.
Um
>> good morning, Ted.
>> Please like, follow, and share the show,
guys. Um, go ahead and like I said, I'm
going to put up that uh I'm going to put
up that uh URL for people who want to
throw Robbie a little extra scratch,
which uh he needs. And but we do really
thank you for uh kicking in that
thousand uh for the month of January.
So, we'll be back after this talking
about this again at the beginning of
February. That's the deal. We raised
$1,000 a month from him. Um before we
get into it, um our junior producer,
um he has uh he he's asking me to remind
you that if you become a tier 2 YouTube
member, uh by by this coming Friday, um
you will be able to uh you'll you'll be
able to get credits and you'll be able
to uh you can also buy YouTube
merchandise through the site through
YouTube um for the
And here is the one of the first
examples of it, the new deprogram
t-shirt. Um, handsome black simple punk
rock just like us. Um, and uh, so
anyway, go to YouTube and do that. But
we want you to watch watch us on Rumble,
so we're making it as complicated as
possible. Um, you know. [laughter]
Yeah.
>> I like it.
>> I like the t-shirt. I'm gonna get I'm
have to get myself one of those myself.
Um, okay. So, all right. So, we should,
of course, as always, please put your
comments, questions, insults, everything
into the YouTube or the Rumble feed, and
we will get to them ASAP. Um, a little
bit of breaking news. The um former
president of South Korea, Yun So, yeah.
>> Um, is apparently facing the death
penalty for his imbecillic attempt
>> to impose martial law. I have a Yun
story. So, I I I was a um I was a uh I
had a job at at an office at Columbia
University's admissions and financial
aid office. My boss, the office manager,
was a Yune from this family that has
>> Oh, really?
>> powerful Korean family in and out
politics for literally centuries,
>> decades. Oh, centuries.
>> Centuries.
>> Okay.
>> Anyway, um one of So, he he had a scroll
that he showed me. He laid rolled out on
his floor. It was an entire family tree
going back a thousand years.
>> You know what? I worked with Yoyo Ma's
son, Nick Ma. We were both on the Senate
Foreign Relations Committee uh staff
together and um we were talking about
genealogy and I was saying how proud I
was that I was able to go back like with
documents to 1799 and then just kind of
with stories to like 1645. And he said,
"Oh, his father has these ancient
scrolls that go back 2,000 years with
their family tree."
>> Yeah.
>> 2,000 years. He said they were found
inside the wall of a mud house that had
been in the family forever.
>> That's cool. So,
>> this was only a [clears throat] mere th
a mere millennium, not two, but
>> crazy though. Anyway, the point is I
remember looking at it and at one point
I found I think it was his grandfather
or great-grandfather and I was like,
"Wait, you're directly descended from
the biggest [__] in Korean history."
He goes, "Yeah." And it was a Yun who
basically had a played an and he's big
part of the reason that the that the
partition happened. Um,
>> wow.
>> I mean, but anyway, [laughter]
>> so I'm like again these Yunes, they keep
popping up like bad pennies. Um,
>> I I like Koreans.
>> I like I like Koreans. They be
>> They love Americans. They work hard.
Their food is fantastic.
>> Their food is great.
>> Yeah.
>> I learned how to juice chopsticks from a
Korean uh roommate in college, Paul.
>> And uh and the thing is, so they eat,
you know, when they eat steak, right?
They love steak. They don't cut it up
first, right? They you literally pick up
the whole piece and you bite it off like
a [laughter] like a caveman. But the
thing is, what I'm really appreciative
of that because it made gave me really
strong uh chopstick chops.
>> I I worked with a guy at the CIA who was
engaged to a Japanese girl and she broke
up with him because she said that he ate
like a Korean the way he used
chopsticks. And he said years later,
he's like I I still don't know what in
the world she meant by that.
>> Oh, no. That's that's what I'm talking
about. Like the the So like the
Japanese, which I also I worked for a
Japanese bank. the Japanese um the that
the the chopsticks are a more delicate
like a surgical implement whereas like
you know you have to kind of like use
some muscle mass to uh to use it Korean
style. Personally, if I if I had to do
it all over again, I'd still do Korean.
Korean method is the best method because
you can do anything, you know, if you
can pick up a heavy piece of beef um you
know, everything else comes easy. So,
>> yeah,
>> that's true.
>> All right, so uh let's see. We got some
question. Let's just do some questions
before we talk about Renee. Good. And or
maybe it will. All right. Uh McKenna
308. Uh we both we both speak about the
importance of independent media. What
are your favorite who are your favorite
independent media sources?
>> Who should we avoid? There's fewer than
there used to be. Go ahead, John.
>> Avoid the Intercept.
>> I don't trust a single one of them. And
in all complete seriousness,
>> I think that they work for or with the
FBI
>> in
>> Well, we certainly know that they worked
with the NSA.
>> You can say that again. Um, I I'm I'm
very proud of uh Consortium News. I
mean, Chris Hedges is there and and Ray
McGovern is there and so many people
whose opinions I respect. So, I I like
Consortium very much. Um, for historical
analysis, CovertAction Magazine, Jeremy
Kusarov is very good. Um,
anti-war.com is good. I like Reason
Magazine, although I don't agree with
everything they say, but even the stuff
I disagree with, they argue it well. How
about you, Ted?
>> Um, I agree with all of those. Um, and
also I agree with your take on the
Intercept. Jesus Christ. Um, this is
total wolf in sheep's clothing. Um I'm
I'm also at who what.org
news but um
>> yeah so and I I do cartoons for them. Uh
so yeah no I I I agree that there's
fewer than there used to be and of
course there's podcasts like this. Um by
the way just some breaking news from the
Hill. It looks like there's that the
fallout over Renee Good could actually
increase the chances of a government
shutdown. A lot of Democrats seem to be
threatening to withhold funding for the
Department of Homeland Security.
>> Wow.
>> In order to demand reforms. So, that's
interesting.
>> That's huge. And like you said last
week, we're three weeks away from
another government shutdown and
literally no one's talking about it.
>> No, I know. And I I was just thinking
about that this morning like these
Democrats, they can do something about a
lot of the stuff that we that we're
talking about here. And that I guess,
you know, this is what it is. They can
shut down the government. They don't
have to pay. They do not have to keep
going. Um Katie Catastrophe, you keep
mentioning your time in the Middle East.
Um were you a traditional journalist
before you got into being a cartoonist?
I have worn that hat. Um but no, I've
been a cartoonist first. Uh I my first
cartoons were published when I was 15
years old in the Ketaring, Ohio, uh
Oakwood Times. But um definitely uh I've
done straight journalism uh at various
publications um throughout over the
years, but I I kind of view it as two
things. I have the journalist hat and I
have the cartoonist hat. So um you know
they're they're not the same. Also,
although sometimes they're the same
philos philosopher chief question,
another one for me. Would you consider
making a cartoon where you and John are
the characters? Sure,
100%.
>> [laughter]
>> I mean, full disclosure, I mean, John
and I are going to be working on a book
together. That's pros, but I can speak
graphic novel or
>> Hey, and I want to say something uh on
the record and in front of everybody
because I I know what you're like and I
know what your response would be if we
were talking about this privately. So,
um, so I I want to commission you to do
a a cartoon of, not a cartoon, but like
a portrait of me that that I want to
use, um, as my as my screen for, uh,
Deep Focus.
>> That's awesome.
>> And the reason I say publicly is because
I know you wouldn't charge me and I want
to pay a normal the normal rate that
anybody would pay if they just stumble
on your website.
>> John, you don't have to do that.
>> I know, but I want to.
>> All right. Well, I appreciate that.
We'll we'll talk about it. Uh definitely
if I charge you anything, it'll be the
friends [laughter] rate because there's
a friends rate and then there's the
enemies rate and then there's the sort
of corporist rate and [laughter] those
are all different numbers. Um and I will
not anyway I probably will I'll try to
convince you not to take my money. Um I
mean not to not to send me your money.
Uh but yes, I would totally do that.
John, we'll talk about tell me the specs
later. So a dollar. Thank you so much.
LA punk versus NYC punk. BR versus
British punk. So, I love them all. I
love X. I love the Ramones. I love this.
I love the Sex Pistols, but I've and and
I love the Dictators, big New York punk
band. Um, but I gota probably go British
punk, really. Um, and I also really like
San Francisco punk like the Dead
Kennedy's. How about you, John?
>> I gotta ask you, I'm I'm Listen, I'm
stuck. I'm stuck in the mid 1970s.
Every single morning, seven days a week,
when I wake up, the first words out of
my mouth are, and I have to spell it, A
L E XA because she'll turn herself on.
Uh, play 70s on Seven. And she says 70s
on Seven by SiriusXM. And I just lay
there in bed.
>> You would have liked You would have
liked the Ted R studio this morning. I
was blasting Moth the Hoople.
>> I love Moth the Hoopal. I saw him at the
hoople at George Washington University
in 1982. But my point is,
and I listened to Casey Kasem every
single weekend. They do a different
year, but on that day, on that date,
every weekend, this past weekend was
1970. The weekend before was 1978. The
weekend before that was 73. But I I I
just I never graduated into punk because
I was stuck in mid70s rock.
>> That's interesting. Um, you know, I I
was because I'm a year older than you.
Yeah.
>> Um, and maybe that made the difference,
but like for me, I was waiting dying,
you know, I was dying in the as a kid
when I was 12, dying in the in the in
the in the ocean of Prague rock. And I
hated that stuff. And and then when I
first heard like the New York Dolls,
Blondie, yeah, early Talking Heads, DVO,
all that stuff, it was totally like my
mind was open like this is what I've
been waiting for. Um, so and I, you
know, for a while there in the late '7s,
there was this kind of like once you
went punk, you didn't go back to like,
you know, classic rock. You're not going
to listen to Zep anymore. But now I
don't feel that way at all. I feel like
it's all the same. It's all, like Billy
Joel would say, it's all rock and roll
to me. It
>> Yeah. When I got to college, I started
college a year later that a year after
you did. Um, so I was I started in ' 82
and by then, you know, 70s rock was
gone, '7s pop was pretty much gone or
going
>> and I remember wave.
>> Freshman year, it was all new wave. I
freshman year there was like a mixer,
the drinking age in DC was 18 at the
time, New York.
>> So we were all 18. So, I remember going
to this mixer and somebody was blasting
Safety Dance. You remember that awful,
awful song?
>> Men in Hats if you want to. You can
leave the past behind.
>> I remember thinking, I want to shoot
myself [laughter] rather than listen to
the rest of this song.
>> And now,
>> that was a really [__] stupid song.
It's
>> And it's retro. It's back in style. I
don't understand.
>> Well, there were a lot of stupid one hit
wonders uh during that period. Um, but
you know, I have to admit I might not
change the channel if that came on now.
[laughter]
Like I have to say I like the
instrumentals.
Um, [laughter] but you know, but the but
the music's so dumb. The lyrics are so
dumb. So dumb.
>> You can dance if you want to. Oh my god.
Like what a stupid Anyway, that's just
me.
>> Yeah. No, no, no. It's not you. You're
you're you're right about that. That's
objective truth. Um, ex Ryan John. Does
Trump want a civil war? Um, look, get
into the Renee. I mean, John, I was just
thinking about this this morning, right?
I was looking at like the White House,
the official White House, the official
Homeland Security Twitter feeds, and
it's like the thing is I've never seen a
government that tries to raise the
temperature before. when when the uh
White House spokeswoman is asked a
question and uh her response is your
mother. What do you think of that?
>> You know you're in trouble.
>> Yeah.
>> That's that's seriously your official
response from the White House. Your
mother.
>> It's I mean they're they're trying to
raise the temperature. Yeah. This is
part of their I mean so you know what do
you think John? I mean
>> I they don't want a civil war obviously
[laughter] because because they would be
part of it you know.
>> Excuse me. One second. Phil Chat says,
"I pictured John with flock of seagull's
hair." Um, [laughter]
freshman year spring fling it was called
in the quad.
>> Now that is a good song. I ran so far
away from you.
>> The the the band was Flock of Seagulls.
And I remember calling my brother and
saying, "Oh my god, I'm in heaven. I
just saw Flock of Seagulls and it was
free."
>> Sorry.
>> Yeah. [laughter] I was I was so
disappointed that the rest of the album
wasn't as good as that as that single.
Now, that's not true about certain one
hit wonders like like the vapors.
Remember Turning Japanese?
>> Oh my god. Yeah.
>> But their other shit's great actually,
but just nobody listens to it.
>> No, that's that's true. Sorry. To get
back to your uh
>> my Civil War uh thing, you know. I think
that if he does,
he doesn't even realize that he does. M
>> and I I keep coming back to this New
York Times interview that they did with
Trump day before yesterday in which
three separate times they asked him who
was advising him and um and uh
[laughter]
and um three times he said he doesn't
take advice from anybody which I don't
fully believe but he said he doesn't
take advice. Whatever his gut tells him
that's what he does. He's He's only
constrained by his own morality.
That's
>> what he told the New York Times.
>> Yeah, that's it. [snorts] He's only
constrained by his own morality.
>> That's like That's also not true. That
That's not true because it can't be
true.
>> Um, Desert Fox, a question for both of
us. Where do we stand on the Iran war?
The fleet movements don't lie, but I
don't think that normal logic applies.
Thanks for the amazing work and riveting
yet sober insight.
>> I'm glad you brought that up. So, go
ahead, answer it. And while you're
talking, I'm going to find this
magnificent uh website that somebody
sent me yesterday.
>> Okay. Um All right. Well, so look,
here's the thing. Like, if you missed
the show yesterday, uh as John pointed
out, uh you know, our our our the fleet
movements are constrained to the
southern uh Caribbean. We're still
[__] around with the Venezuelans and
we're busy over there. So, if anyone's
going to attack Iran right now, it's
probably going to be our proxies, the
Israelis, or arguably our bosses, the
Israelis, depending on how you look at
it. Um,
>> and so in terms of
>> here's the thing, right? Like, we don't
there is no Iran war now. And I guess we
should talk about what the situation is.
I mean, we're hearing a lot of uh, you
know, very overheated analysis about how
we're at the brink of revolution. Now,
the thing is like Robert F. Kennedy, as
Robert F. Kennedy um famously observed
you kind of don't know if a revolution
is a revolution appears inevitable after
it happened impossible before it
happens. I think that's very true. Um
the thing is also I agree with your
analysis yesterday though John 100% I
thought about it more and more after we
talked here on the air. I don't see Iran
uh having another 1979 style, and I
don't mean ideologically, but like a
unified national revolution. I see
disintegration. I see um civil conflict
more looking like Libya. Um yeah, you
know, well, you know,
>> because there's no center
>> there. There is no center. These
demonstrations uh started in Kurdistan
because reportedly that's where the most
Israeli agents are located. Um, so
they've they've moved to some of the
major cities, but um,
but and an Iranian in Iran said this
morning to somebody that I'm close to
that uh, you know, they keep hearing
reports of these thousands of people now
dead. And he he said
it's just not happening. These
demonstrations are are isolated. They're
smallcale. Yes, there are deaths. A lot
of them are um are caused by the police.
A lot of them are caused by the
demonstrators. And I mentioned yesterday
these demonstrators and there's
confirmation from the Israelis today
that these are Mossad um agitators. Uh
they're bragging about it in the in the
Israeli papers. and Mike Pompeo um
posted on on Twitter that it's the
Israelis, but they're burning they're
they're burning the fire trucks. They're
going to fire stations and they're
throwing Molotov cocktails at the fire
trucks so that when they light fires in
buildings to burn the buildings down and
get people agitated, they can't put the
fire out. That's an Israeli tactic. It's
a well-known Israeli tactic. I was going
to say that's not the tactic of of your
standard um uprising kind of notion.
>> No, it's not. And and may I add one
thing? So I this fantastic site that
gives you up totheminute locations of
every aircraft carrier. Remember we said
that if you really want to know if the
United States is going to attack another
country, look at naval movements because
we never ever attack anybody's if
anybody if we don't have an aircraft
carrier battle group or two or six um
nearby. So, the USS Nimttz is uh in
Washington State on its way to Norfick,
Virginia. The USS Dwight Eisenhower uh
is in Norfolk. The USS Carl Vincent is
in San Diego. The USS Theodore Roosevelt
is in San Diego. The USS Abraham Lincoln
is in the South China Sea. The USS
George Washington
is off the coast of Japan. USS John
Stennis
is being repaired in Newport News,
Virginia. The USS Harry S. Truman is off
the east coast of the United States. The
USS Ronald Reagan
is being repaired in Puget Sound. USS
George HW Bush is on its way to Norfolk
from Jacksonville, Florida. USS Gerald
Ford is off the coast of Puerto Rico. We
cannot attack Iran.
There are no naval support vessels.
>> Can't do it.
>> And and we don't have a And there isn't
a base, an air base of any size that we
have access to close enough to it,
right?
>> No, that's right.
>> So, yeah, that's interesting. I mean,
what do you make of those of uh I mean,
most of it a lot of uh vessels heading
to or at Norfolk may retooling repairs.
>> Yes, several of them are being um
completely refurbished. Uh, some are
being um sold for a penny. I read
online. I can even tell you which ones.
They're being sold for a penny. That's
the USS John F. Kennedy, USS Enterprise,
USS Constellation, and the USS
Kittyhawk. All were sold for 1 cent to
International Ship Breaking Limited, and
they're going to be taken apart
uh panel by panel and sold for scrap.
>> Huh. I was going to say like uh you know
Pete Davidson probably should have
bought one of those instead of Staten
Island Fairy.
>> Staten Island Ferry
>> for hundreds of thousands of dollars.
>> Yeah. That he can't get out of.
>> Yeah. Well, that was like how I know he
said he was high. I actually believe
him. Um how high were you, dude? We want
that gan.
>> That's right. Because a transaction like
that doesn't take an hour. [laughter]
>> Yeah. I mean if you're high for an hour.
Okay.
>> Right. Right. Good point. Good point. I
guess you might just tell your your
assistant to do it, right?
>> You know, like people say, "Oh, I got
this t tattoo because I was drunk." It's
like, dude, that tattoo must have taken
eight hours to get on you. [laughter]
>> What do you mean you were drunk?
>> How drunk?
>> How drunk could you possibly have been?
>> Or maybe you're drunk when you start and
then by the time you're trying to sober
up, you're like, I can't have a half
tattoo. You know,
>> I mean, that would be the worst. Um,
Zack Diecast uh says that my take on
Renee Good is so libtard normmy crap
crap all all caps. I' I'd like some
details. I mean, I I'm not sure he or
she knows what my take is on this. I
mean, look, you look, here's the thing.
Even if we stipulate that shooting is
unjustified for the simple reason that
like there is no evidence whatsoever of
what I mean, let's just say that she's
guilty of everything they say. She's
obstructing law enforcement. She's not
compliant.
She drove to drove toward the dude. The
fact is she he fired at her as she was
going by. Okay, so like even if she hit
him, okay, that threat is now a past
threat because it's already happened and
there's no evidence that happened
anyway. So the point is he didn't have
any right to shoot her. Now we could say
that like so I think a a grand jury and
a jury should adjudicate this. Could it
be complicated? Sure. Uh could he
possibly walk? Sure. But I but I think
it deserves, you know, 12 men and women,
good and true, to look at it. That was
>> I was watching a legal analyst last
night on um Jake Tapper. And um he said
that this was obviously a homicide, not
necessarily a murder. And to tell you
the honest to God's truth,
>> I never thought about the difference
between the two. A homicide is simply
defined as a person who is killed by
another person.
>> Yeah,
>> that's a homicide. A murder is when you
intentionally kill the other person.
>> Mhm.
>> But of course,
>> if someone by negligence usually
>> Yeah, that's right. But if you shoot
somebody in the face,
what do you think is going to happen?
>> Right. It's a homicide.
>> It should be investigated. Yeah. And and
I guess let's let's talk about that. I
mean, that was our main topic today. Um,
so I mean, here's the thing. The the the
government is, you know, abandoning all
attempt to have us believe that they're
engaged in a fair process, right? The
president, the vice president, the
secretary of homeland security all
within hours defended the ICE agent. Um,
the the social media feeds for the
administration have been going rolling
night and day to defend him. Uh, and and
they're smearing her. I love how they
dehumanize her. They call her this
individual.
>> This individual. I noticed the same
thing
>> instead of, you know, you don't have to
say this mother of three, but you could
have just said this person, uh, this
this woman, you know, anything like
that, but they don't do that. Um, this
individual domestic terrorist anyway.
And now the latest, so the, um, the
Minneapolis and the Minnesota
authorities have both been frozen out of
what has become inexplicably a federal
investigation. Um and now um the DOJ
normally in incidents like this has
civil rights experts which I think is
confusing to people because they think
civil rights relates to racial issues
but correct it doesn't. Your civil
rights are like your first amendment
right to free speech is a civil right
>> and to if if you kill somebody and it's
charged as a violation of their civil
rights, you're still talking about life
without parole,
>> right?
>> It's a very serious charge. I mean, your
your second amendment right to own a
firearm is a civil right. Um, people
don't, you know, so the thing is that um
those civil rights people normally uh
that their team participates in an
investigation like this and they're they
have been frozen out. That just doesn't
happen. I mean,
the tr the the the administration does
not seem to care uh about being
perceived as as as fair or not having
their thumb on the scale.
>> Yeah. Does that matter? I mean, I feel
like it does matter.
>> I think it matters. I think it matters.
And, you know, I was I gave this a lot
of thought last night. Um,
Donald Trump's not going to be president
forever. Republicans aren't going to be
president forever. There's no statute of
limitation on murder. There's no statute
of limitation on civil rights
violations. And so really
all we have to wait for is a Democrat to
get into the White House and the
Democrat to order that the Justice
Department turn over primacy in the case
to the state of Minnesota and then this
guy screwed.
>> Assuming the Democrats have the balls to
do that,
>> assuming and we should say that's a big
assumption. [laughter]
>> I don't trust any of them.
>> Yeah. No, I mean with good reason. Um
Peruse. Hey John and Ted, thanks for the
show. Have you met Jeffrey Saxs? And
could it be possible to get him as a
guest on the show? I have
>> We should We should try. I met him once
on a podcast. We should try to get him.
I think that would be a lot of fun.
>> Robbie, let's try to Robbie, can you can
you reach out to Jeffrey Sachs for us?
>> Okay. Thank you, Robbie.
>> Awesome.
>> Okay. All right. So, um Okay. Uh
for John Fra from Fasmatas regarding the
intercept but more broadly what are your
thoughts on Pierre Omid Omidar? Oh don't
I get to have thoughts about Pier?
>> Yeah. Yeah. No you you have very
wellconsidered thoughts on billionaires.
You go first.
>> Well so Pier Omidar is um what's the
phrase? A lying sack of [__] So if you
go to YouTube and look I recommend that
anybody do this. Look up the intercept
um launch video for first look media.
Look first look media inter uh launch
video. It is it'll make you laugh. So
basically it's Pierre Odar talking about
how he's launching a new media company.
This is about 10 years ago in which
they're going to do everything. We're
like the media's in crisis. That's true.
And we need an independent voice with
hard-hitting asskicking journalists. So
we're going to do everything new fin.
We're going to have a whole team doing
financial reporting. We're even going to
do sports, culture, you know, weather
>> joke,
>> everything, right? Like a giant. We're
reinventing the media
>> because he's a billionaire and he can
afford it.
>> HE HAS. YEAH. I have billions to spare.
I love America. I love the world. I love
press freedom. I want everybody to go
wild and crazy. Right. So, um, my, um,
my, so, so when that all happened, IT
TURNED OUT LIKE, WELL, WHEN we said
there's going to be 15 different
channels, what we really mean is one.
And [laughter]
so anyway, then my buddy who um, worked
over there calls me up and he goes, "Oh,
would you like to come on as like a
graph as like a a comics journalist
slashed editorial cartoonist columnist?"
I'm like, "I'm in." Um, so I don't hear
back and like basically he keeps So he's
getting more and more pissed. He's like,
"Our budget went from 20 to 10 to five
to $1 million." At a certain point,
Pierre is weighing in on the office
furniture, saying that the office
furniture is too expensive. And
basically, the thing shriveled away to a
to like a fraction of a fraction of a
fraction of what he promised. And the
thing is for no particular reason, just
cuz he's a control freak and he wanted
to make a big splash, but he didn't want
to actually spend his money. And then
that's not getting into the fact that,
you know, he has like, you know, he
wasn't he wasn't going to do what you
would need a billionaire to do. Throw
money at it and then don't check in,
right? Just make sure your money's being
spent, right? Maybe, but like, you know,
basically, you shouldn't have your thumb
on the scale like the way that, you
know, Bezos is on the editorial page of
the Washington Post. Oh, I can't. I'm
>> disgusting.
>> I would have cancelled my post uh
subscription except that we do this
show.
>> We have to have it.
>> And we I have to have it.
>> Me, too.
>> Oh, I can't.
>> But but so the thing is so that that's
my so I think Pier Beddr is completely
full of [__] Yeah, basically.
>> I have to agree. [snorts] I have to
agree. Um, you know, in the very
beginning when they were still at the
$20 million phase, I was like, "Okay,
this is this is actually going to be
cool." Even though he's a billionaire, I
thought, "Ah, if he gives them, you
know, editorial freedom like he promised
he would."
>> I thought, "Okay, this is going to be
this is going to be all right." And then
almost instantaneously, it just became a
lie. But that's not my biggest beef with
um with The Intercept. I've I've said
this a million times. I've written about
it. The Intercept The Intercept's
reporters
have been personally responsible for
sending five whistleblowers to prison.
Five whistleblowers.
>> Reality winner. Jeffrey Sterling. me,
um, Daniel Hail,
and who's the fifth?
I can't remember. Anyway, it's five.
Take my word for it. Um, I tweeted at
them when they outed reality winner,
and that was the most egregious of all
the cases.
>> Ridiculous.
amateurish behavior by two
self-professed
professional national security
journalists. What a croc of [__]
>> Idiots.
>> And let's name them. It's Matthew Cole
and and uh Rich Espazito.
Shame. Shame on that.
>> By the way, I should never work in
journalism again.
>> Never ever. Matthew Cole fancies himself
an author. Um, Rich Espazito went he
left journalism to become the deputy uh
police commissioner of New York.
>> Appropriate.
>> Isn't that appropriate?
>> So yeah, I tweeted at them and I said I
said
>> these are the kinds of people, by the
way, that the Intercept hires.
>> That's right. I said, "Hey, Intercept,
serious question.
You must be working for the FBI, right?
Because nobody can be that stupid."
And I got hundreds of responses. They
were like the only ones who didn't
respond,
>> of course.
>> Uhhuh.
>> I mean, you know, it's it's it's horrid.
Um, okay. Cooper duper, [laughter]
thanks for this question. Although Renee
Good's passing was tragic. Do you think
that the mainstream media and social
media is hyping it up to distract from
the fraud allegations? Okay. So, people,
you guys know I'm a lefty. Um, in part,
yes, I do think that. Um, I mean, this
is a this is look, this is if you're
Governor Tim Walls, this is a you're
maybe not happy to see a Minnesotan
taxpayer get blown away on the streets
of a suburb, but I'm not going to go
that far. I don't think he's that evil,
but you're not unhappy to see the
Somalia stuff uh, you know, washed off
the the headlines. Um, I I think it's
it's a it's part of it. I I do think
it's kind of like we only have room, you
know, the Americans only have room for
one Minnesota story in their brain and
let's let's have this one be the story.
I I do think that's true.
>> Yeah, I think that's right.
>> Um
Frazz, how on earth do you have an
Alexa? Like the privacy factor
is that they can be used as evidence in
event of an emergency. Yeah, in all
seriousness, um I I just have one in the
bedroom where nothing is going on.
[laughter] So, um the way that sounds,
>> so I don't mind if she listens to me
because, you know, it's just me
[laughter] snoring, I guess.
>> I'm There's too many places I can go
with [laughter] that comment, John. I'm
not going to. Oh my god. Um USA Navy
vet, what are we talking about here?
Gossip. Are we talking about world
affairs? I don't know. I uh maybe I got
a tune out of this. Uh it doesn't make
any sense what's going on here. It's
important issues. Americans can't eat.
Fair. Okay.
>> Yes. True. Americans can't eat. And we
can and Okay. We [laughter] That's true.
No. Seriously, it is a major problem.
But I mean, I'm sorry. I'm not going to
apologize for uh breaking out. John and
I are both [laughter] usually very
grimlike people. And so here here I'm
not usually accused of being too joyful.
I don't know about [clears throat] you,
John.
>> Hey, um our buddy Mike from Nottingham
uh wrote uh in the chat that uh Oh,
shoot. Let me find it. I think uh I got
it from um
from Robbie.
Help me out. It's about uh it's a UK
question
>> here. Here, I'm going to Robbie. Do you
know?
>> There it is. I got it. I got it. Peter
Mendlesson on the BBC saying he was
blind to Epstein's crimes because he
himself, Mandlesson, is gay. It's as
laughable as [laughter] it's Andrew
interview. Oh my god. Mandles, think
about that. I mean, everybody knows
Mandlesson's gay. Nobody gives a [__]
So, he's justifying having been to the
island because And it it's okay because
he's gay.
And all the underage
kids were girls.
>> Ah,
>> so it's cool. No worries.
>> Yeah. Because if you just know about it,
that's that's okay.
>> Yeah, that's right. You don't have to
tell anybody. Somebody else will tell.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Exactly. That's all that's I
I'm obsessed with that whole idea that
somebody else will. like, you know, um
we we we're going to replace all our
employees with uh you know, people from
overseas and AI, but but like someone
else will hire a real Americans for real
jobs. Someone else will do it. It's
always someone else will take care of
it. Um you know, as a journalist, I
mean,
>> it would be icky for me to take on this
difficult story uh that would challenge
the official narrative, but some other
journalist will do it. Don't worry.
Don't worry, John. some other lawyer
will will take you on. Exactly. Not me.
>> Exactly. Right.
>> Um, aren't Americans too lazy and chill
to fight a civil war? James Turner.
Well, we did. [laughter]
>> So, um, I don't know. Um, I don't think
I I you know, look, I I do think we are
a lazy folk uh, intellectually, but I
don't think there could be a civil war,
but I think you need different dynamic
than we have. You know, we have to have
like you you need organizations. I keep
coming back to that. Nobody likes to
hear it. Um, Soden, thanks so much for
the $49.99.
>> Oh my gosh. Thank you. Thank you.
>> Good morning, John and Ted. While I sip
on this morning cocktail, I work nights
lol. Can you please tell us? I actually,
you know, I used to work uh I used to
live right on the same street as the New
York Times, 43rd Street, uh which New
York Times was between uh seventh and
eighth. I was between 8th and 9th. And
there was a bar that all the New York
Times like press workers would kick off
to. And I would see them, you know,
drinking hard like at, you know, seven
in the morning when I was on my way to
my office job. Uh, anyway, kind of
funny. Um, can you please tell us where
the US went wrong with the Shaw back in
the day?
>> I would love to hear from you guys who
are alive at that time and how everyone
dropped the ball.
>> Take it away, John. [snorts] Wow. Where
do you even begin? The Sha was an
absolute monarch, absolute dictator. He
had a bloodthirsty
intelligence service called Savak that
spent way more time investigating and
murdering Iranian citizens than it ever
did doing anything, you know, in any
other country. Um, he had formal
official diplomatic relations with
Israel, which really pissed people off.
Um, he was perfectly happy to send
Iran's oil to the United States and to
the UK. uh and you know Iran very
briefly had a democratic governor uh
government rather rather it was prime
minister uh Muhammad Masadic and the US
and UK overthrew Mosadic in 1953.
The the sha had been um or his father
had been in power then the sha was
briefly in power then Mosadic won an
election he was deposed and spent the
literally the rest of his life under
house arrest. the Shaw was forcibly
reimposed on the Iranian people and then
by 1979
it it all fell apart. He he went on a
ski vacation in February of 79 and never
went back.
>> Yeah. I all that and I think what's the
the one chapter that's kind of missing
from this is because ultimately uh of
the way that the revolution played out
we kind of forget the role of like
socialists and other leftists and other
the anti-Shaw alliance was very was very
>> very broad
>> and it included a lot of opposition
figures and they organized you know
thoroughly and consistently
um for you know at least at least 5 to
10 years against the sha and you know
the sha was a US um you know UK puppet
and um and the Iranians are proud people
and I mean and you know they wanted
national sovereignty and and you know
the shot and the shot was a desperate
>> yeah he was he was desperate he really
was
>> yeah and and Savak was brutal um one of
my mom's classmates at Wright State
University was an Iranian um refugee uh
he was a political refugee uh he was a
political dissident against the sha. He
um went home for uh vacation one uh
during one of the breaks and the Sabak
guys kidnapped him, amputated both of
his legs and dropped off his bleeding
body at it in front of his parents' door
in Tehran.
>> Oh my god.
>> That's what they were like. Um
uh let's see. Um what have we heard
about this John and Marjorie? Have we
heard about the theory that Trump has
dementia? Starting to show more and more
symptoms. He's definitely not the same
as he was.
>> I've heard that. No. And and the White
House has never explained these uh MRIs
that he's getting up at uh uh what's the
Naval Hospital in Bethesda.
>> Oh. Uh
>> Bethesd Bethesda Naval Medical Center.
>> Yeah, that one.
>> Right. That one. Yeah.
Something's up.
>> Yeah. I mean, look, he's getting older.
I mean, you know, he's he wasn't the
same in the 90s as he was in the 80s or
in the odds as he was in the 90s and so
on. We are all getting older. Uh but
something is up and I don't know what it
is. It's not playing out the way Biden
did. With Biden, it was like you just
couldn't miss it. Um because you know
Trump's still energetic.
>> Yes,
>> he is.
>> Ray, thanks for the buck. John, what's
your take on Carg Island uh and its
significance for Iran. Heard that it
would get hit, that it would destroy the
world, if it got hit, it would destroy
the world's oil economy and other
repercussions.
Yeah, Kar Island is where
most of Iran's oil is refined and
it was bombed in the in the
[clears throat] 1980s.
It it caused a a global oil price shock.
Um
it's it's possible that that the West,
meaning the United States andor Israel,
could bomb it again. Um, if if that were
to happen, I think the Iranians, having
learned their lesson in earlier decades,
uh, would come out swinging and it would
just be a crisis for oil prices.
>> Robbie, we got an ad.
Okay. Uh, when whenever you're ready.
Um, okay. So, uh, let's see. Um, Elliot
Covert, John, murder is actually defined
by malice of forethought, which is a
vague legal term. Yeah,
>> sometimes you can commit murder by acts
of indifference to human life, eg drunk
driving. But murder is also defi and all
the different subsets of it are defined
differently depending on the
jurisdiction.
>> That's right.
>> That's a good point.
>> So, um, you know, but
>> I mean, by the way, I don't think drunk
driving is technically considered
murder, right?
>> I don't think it is.
>> I think it's considered a form of
manslaughter.
>> Yeah. That's why they call it vehicular
homicide
>> rather than vehicular murder. [snorts]
Um,
>> yeah,
>> I could look at Well, I if anyone knows
differently, let us know. Uh, great
battis, what do you think about Federman
supporting the Greenland takeover?
>> Federman,
>> you know, Federman supporting the
Greenland takeover came two days after
Federman announced that he was not going
to support the Greenland takeover.
>> Speaking of dementia, I'm trying to be
kind to the guy, but he's clearly brain
damaged
>> and he should not be in the Senate. No,
>> he's not in [snorts] his right mind.
>> No.
>> And he's he's embarrassing himself and
the state.
>> Yep.
>> Almost his whole life is falling apart.
His staff is all left. His wife has
broken up with him. I mean, you know, we
don't even know if he's still like talks
to his children. He's a [__] mess.
[clears throat]
>> Yeah, he's a mess.
>> And unfortunately, he's in because he's
a mess, he's in no position to
understand that he's a mess.
>> Yeah, that's that's exactly right.
>> Um, Fasmat tricky question for you,
John. Would you support Dr. Oz as
senator. If we could go back to the
election, I certainly would. Not as a
doctor, just as a person.
>> The guy the guy served in the Turkish
special forces. This is not just that
it's Turkey. It's not for me. But not
just because it's Turkey. This is
exactly why I would never vote for for
Josh, what's his name? Uh the governor.
Because he served in the IDF.
So, you don't serve your country, the
United States, but you're going to run
and serve Israel, or serve in the
Turkish special forces after having
gotten your American citizenship. No.
No. To both of them. I would rather
write in, you know, Ralph Nater or
somebody.
>> Yeah, that's the thing, too, right? Like
in a binary system, you don't really
have to choose one or the other. Uh,
John, why can't the US attack Iran using
only ground bases in the Middle East?
Doesn't the US have a lot of bases? Are
those not enough? Why not?
>> Those are not enough because we don't
have enough um missiles and we don't
have enough uh uh planes. You know, the
aircraft carrier battle groups or the
carriers themselves carry so many planes
and then and then the support ships are
full of literally everything you would
need to fight a war. Look at it this
way. Um, in 1990 and 911,
we bombed Iraq mercilessly for over a
month. To use Colin Powell's uh
terminology, we bombed them back into
the stone age, right? But it wasn't
until we started using our naval assets
>> that we really had them on the run. And
then that's why the ground war only took
but what 42 hours I think it was.
>> Yeah. Yeah. Super super super super
enlightening. Talk about Blitzkrieg. All
right, let me let me read this ad.
You've probably noticed Rumble is
growing fast and it's not slowing down.
They're building a real alternative to
big tech that puts creators first and
actually protects free speech. And now
there's Rumble Premium, an easy way to
upgrade your experience. With premium,
you get adree viewing across the
platform. No pre-rolls, no
interruptions, just the content you came
for. Plus, premium members unlock
exclusive content like bonus videos,
behind the scenes drops, and more from
your favorite creators. Right now,
Rumble is offering 10 bucks off an
annual subscription. Just go to
rumble.com/premium and use the promo
code studio at checkout. That's
rumble.com/premiums promo code studio.
No ads, more freedom and content you
actually care about. That's the deal.
Um, so uh we we should talk about Grock.
Uh, we talked about a little bit. Um, I
use Grock. Full disclosure, I'm a paid
member of uh for uh of X. Um, so you
know, it's not like I'm opposed to it.
Uh, Malaysia and Indonesia became the
first countries in the world. Um, you
Malaysia is a Muslim. Well, they're both
Muslim countries. Huge Muslim countries.
>> Huge.
>> And, um, there so they're very
conservative. Malaysia is more
conservative than Indonesia.
>> Yeah.
>> Um, but uh, so they're they're blocking
Grock over deep fake porn. Um,
what can or should big tech do about it?
I mean, they could seriously program um
the there's already all sorts of blocks
on what Grock or other, you know, uh
image generate text to image generators
will make for you. Like for example, if
you ask it to create Nazi imagery, uh it
it won't do it for the most part. Um so
you can do that. you can program it to
just not create these deep fake nudes
and stuff that have been making like
young girls lives miserable in like
public schools. Um why don't they do
that?
I mean this doesn't serve any purpose.
Um or is it just that they know that
there's money to be made?
>> That that's got to be it, right? I mean
why would you do something like that for
fun? I I don't get it. It it's it's got
to be a money maker somehow. But then at
the same time, any [__] would know that
the government's going to come after
you. You're gonna you're gonna have it
shut down.
>> Yeah, that's the thing, right? Like
possession of um so I have a a colleague
um uh who we will call Darren Bell
because his name is Darren [laughter]
Bell who was arrested for possession of
uh child pornography. Um he's a PEL
surprisewinning editorial cartoonist,
I'm ashamed to say. Um he got an award.
I can't get apparently. Um, and he uh,
you know, he was arrested for possession
of both conventional child porn and AI
generated child porn. And that was part
of what made the case interesting from a
legal point of view. He's one of the
very first cases in the US of someone to
be arrested for uh, you know, child porn
that's u created by AI. Um it's is it um
I guess the question is here
[sighs]
[gasps] I don't even know how to put
this. It's sort of like
how does society meant to deal with
this? I mean you could it spreads a
terri it no one no specific person was
harmed. However, it's a harmful message
to to the normalization of this idea is
clearly harmful.
>> Mhm.
>> Is the legal system able to respond
>> to a problem like that?
>> Well, that's a good question. And you
know, honestly, I think that the legal
system, whether it's in the United
States or in Malaysia and Indonesia,
wherever it is, is going to have to
constantly play catchup on these issues
because the technology is changing so
quickly. I mean, even two years ago,
just two years ago, nobody knew what AI
was. Nobody knew what it could do or how
it was going to change things. It's
putting people out of work now. College
professors are are redundant. We don't
need people to teach us how to write
poetry because the machine does it. Now
with porn, I mean, it's human nature, I
think, to just any new invention to try
to figure out how can use it to to
generate porn. But um
>> true, [laughter]
>> but otherwise I I I think it's just
things are changing too quickly that
that these governments and corporations
can't keep up.
Um, good question from Vermicious
Canids. Uh, is there no justification or
desire for the US to have a stronger
physical presence in Greenland? Or is
that just Cold War era thinking? Let me
just say before Donald Trump brought
this up, the amount of Americans who
gave this any thought on a day-to-day
basis was 0.00001%.
[snorts]
>> Yeah. [laughter]
I mean, nobody. Nobody [clears throat]
thought of this or was like, "Yeah, you
know what? We really got to have we
really got to have Greenland to keep
ourselves safe." Um, you know, and it's
like, uh, is there a justification,
>> Ted? This has to be about this has to be
about, um, the rare earth metals, right?
I remember yesterday we were talking
about
>> drilling in the Arctic.
>> It has to be.
We talked yesterday about this. The
>> Northwest Passage is now open.
Yeah, that's true. It's now open. But uh
the the US has always had access to uh
to Greenland. The the base was given to
us in whatever it was 1940 or 41 to
protect uh Greenland from the Nazis. Uh
we've had the air base, you know, for
for many decades. We we've had the right
to create bases for many decades
>> and we used to have more of a presence
and we withdrew
>> under both Democratic and Republican
administrations.
>> Yes.
>> But we can literally we we don't even
really have to ask permission, right? We
can just call the Danes and say, "Hey,
we'd be sending some more guys and and
they're like, okay, that's it under the
terms of the agreement." So, is there
justification? Sure. The justification
is that 1951 treaty.
>> Yeah, it is. Exactly. But that's the
thing is that that treaty makes it
impossible to understand the need or the
desire on the part of Trump to own it. I
think Trump wants to be able to say that
he added to US territory. I think that
he he's he's old enough to remember
like, you know, Alaska and Hawaii as new
states. And I think he wants those and
he wants uh he wants to be a president
who added territory to the United
States.
>> Yes, I think that's right.
>> Yeah.
>> And it's a lot of territory. Yes,
>> although useless for the most part, but
you know, um, longtime listener, it'd be
one thing if Shapiro served in the IDF,
but still pro protected ci Pennsylvania
Pennians civil liberties, but he
threatened to send in the National Guard
to pro Palestine college encampments.
Well, that's true. Enzo, John, uh, John,
where are uh, curious on where you stand
in regard to the status of your pardon
and whether you're discouraged or
encouraged as to who's received pardon
thus far? touchy subject, but rooting
for you. And obviously, I will always
remind you that if if it's better not to
comment, it's better not to comment.
>> Yeah, I I will say that I I feel like
I'm very close. I'm talking to all the
right people. Um I am mystified as to
why it hasn't happened. You know, I see
reality TV people and crooked
politicians and actually crooked
politicians who don't
not just don't like uh Donald Trump, but
have complained in the in the media
about Donald Trump even after they uh
received pardons from him. I'm just not
[snorts]
I I'm mystified. I don't know.
>> Well, um we're we're we're [laughter]
pull obviously we're everyone's pulling
for you. Um,
>> thank you.
>> Uh, so we should talk a little bit about
these storms. Uh, this is kind of a
weird climate change meets the Middle
East story, right? So these big I mean,
you know, people don't really realize
that like in Israel and and Palestine,
the weather can be pretty severe. Um,
and um, it can be they get storms, they
get severe. I've been there during like,
you know, when it was in the 30s and the
you know, brutal hard rains, big storms
in the Mediterranean. So, um, big storms
swept through the, uh, all the hundreds
of thousands of people who are living in
tents in Gaza over the last few days,
and it's made their lives even more
miserable than they have been before.
The international press is still not
allowed in by the Israelis. Um, and so,
you know, what are the chances as the is
the ceasefire in danger of taking this
uh, human rights, this humanitarian
story off the headlines? I mean, in a
weird way, um, from a PR standpoint,
wouldn't the Palestinians kind of almost
be better off with the war still going
on?
>> They would certainly be getting more
attention because if you're a Gaza
Palestinian, the war never ended. The
ceasefire is a joke. People are being
killed every day still. And there's
still no not I shouldn't say no food,
there's still not enough food. There's
still a a a terrible lack of of clean
water. There aren't enough medical
supplies. People are unhoused. you know,
there they're there are still bodies
under the rubble. It's a hellscape.
>> Yeah.
>> And we're and we're not talking about it
anymore in the West.
>> That's Yeah. Well, that's huge. All
right. So, just a reminder everyone, if
you we go buy the DProgram t-shirt over
on uh YouTube, I like it.
>> Become a tier 2 member. Uh and there it
is right there. Please like, follow, and
share the show. If you're on YouTube, do
consider after you buying buy the
t-shirt heading over to Rumble because
um you the support your support for the
show goes a lot further for us over here
on Rumble. Um please stay tuned uh for
the TMI show with me Chan coming up
right at 10 o'clock Eastern time in a
matter of seconds. We will be back
tomorrow here on Drogram with Ted R and
John Kuryaku uh at 900 a.m. Eastern
time. So see you then. Thanks so much,
John. Talk to you tomorrow. Take it
easy.
>> Bye.
[music]